What would your daily schedule as a child in Thanh Cong look like?
What did you do?
How did you experience your childhood life back then?
When I imagine here when I was a child, it would specifically be when I was in high school
one.
When I was in elementary school
Thanh Cong area
in my memory it is still,
I think those are the three main locations.
In the morning I had to go to school,
So at that time I will go to Thanh Cong area
on mom's or dad's motorbike.
So at that time I was also half-asleep so the first thing I remembered was the gate
school.
Now, Thanh Cong A Elementary School has been rebuilt, and the old school gate was very different.
very different.
School-- Old Thanh Cong school gate is lower,
Um, there's not much, uh, transportation to and from the old Thanh Cong school. All
More people also walk to school, so there are no motorbikes parked
It's very crowded at the school gate like now.
Ah,
In the past, the sound when I remembered the gate of Thanh Cong school back then was
Usually there will be a security guard's voice and a greeting
Mom greets children, dad greets children, children greet parents and all kinds of things.
Then, ah,
school drums.
The sound of the school drum is also a very good thing. That's because I think it's great
There are many emotions when listening to the sound of the school drum, especially feeling rushed and scared because of coming
late.
Well, especially when I'm at the school gate eating snacks.
In the past, there were two things I really liked at the school gate.
That's it
Go shopping for souvenirs and collectibles like soccer cards or cards
Vinamilk to put in a file. In the past, I mean I always felt that I was
A kid's 'status' and 'wealth' was determined by whether they had more cards than their peers.
So we were always trying to keep up with the trend.
-Do you still have those cards? -I think if you look you will find it
[laughter]. It will be on the third floor, the place,
right near the old chaise longue.
-Go ahead. -Already.
Um, the second thing that I really like at the school gate is a, ah,
a comic book rental shop. Because in the past, it was very difficult to buy stories
reading pictures. Well, when I first learned to read, I felt like I had the ability to read
I have to take advantage of the ability to read [laughter]. And that's also a thing
very good
Parents support it because it also trains their reading and language skills.
That's why in the past, I often rented Doraemon
and rented Greek mythology.
Ah,
Rent about two thousand a day, three thousand a day.
When I was studying, it no longer had that rented store, so when did it lose it?
-That rented store? -I think I rented out the entire first level
probably-
-End of first level. -Or around the end of fourth grade, when
I no longer cared too much about rented comics, I started buying them
comics. The price of comic books in the past has dropped more and more, decreasing day by day
fast. Or maybe our family is getting richer and you don't know. Or everyone can afford it
Pay more for comics. Because it's probably a funnel that people will have to try reading
comic book at the rental shop before people decide to buy it.
Oh, but like what do you think about being in fourth grade
Has it disappeared? From my first to fourth grade, I felt like it was Hanoi
How do people rent comic books? While it's time for me to go to class
one is completely unable to experience that anymore.
I think it depends,
Well, I don't think every school gate will have a comic book rental shop.
The first,
maybe it's unique to the...
I mean, I couldn't find any other comic book rental shop other than the one at the gate
-that school. -It, it is an old culture of Hanoi
-there. -OH.
Uh. But I don't understand why it's still there in my time but not in my time.
-We are four years apart. -Yeah.
I also think about the day when I was in fifth grade, I went to the bookstore to buy stories
Painting it is also quite easy.
But back when... And I thought...
For instance, when I went to pick up vegetables for my mom, I didn't even need to pay on the spot.
range,
I would just say, 'Mom will transfer the money to you later,' and she would pay them later.
Because [laughs] it was like a big family, and people were happy to let you run a tab.
But in general, Doraemon in the past had many short stories and was very readable
quickly. Just leave it under the table and read for two days and then you'll have to rent a new story.
-OK. -So buying comics is very important
-inefficient. -Yeah,
-Yeah, I understand. -Sharing economy.
The first sharing economy model I know before Grab.
-OK [laughter]. -OK.
OK [laughter].
-Where have you been, bro? -Okay, come to the school gate.
Well, below are two, two things I like at the school gate. Oh, do you like snacks?
Older brother
I like to eat snacks, but I just like it. That means I wants to try but many, most
You don't like to eat those things. Once upon a time there was a lipstick cream.
I don't have that either. I have to tell you.
Lipstick is a cream,
A lipstick that looks like a lipstick. That means it makes me feel very good
-adult. -Ah! I remember.
-Turn, turn, turn it up- -Now that child doesn't have that anymore.
After I hit my lips, I licked my lips.
Oh, oh, remember, remember. Did you buy that for me or what?
-Terrible chemistry. -I finished it a while ago in front of my school gate
There is also a store, a store that sells Zoro and games.
-Yes, yo yo. -Yeah, yo yo [laughter]. OK.
Yes, in the past, there were three games that I often bought. One is yo yo,
-two is the spinner. -Yes, yes.
And three is Bakugan. After throwing it out, tmy one will shoot.
No, I don't know that. Only know about the spinning top.
In general, the animation industry seemed to dominate children's toys back in the day
there.
-Yeah. -YES.
Oh, those Chinese movies that keep showing on BBC.
-Already. -What about now? Now-
-Fruit robots of all kinds. -But now there is no longer that style,
-no- -I think it's still there. But now everyone
who will buy merch.
-Yeah, it's like buying- -Give the hexagon on the backpack.
But that's just me as an adult. Italian kids, for example Bean, that's it
won't play the games. Well, he'll probably buy some Skibidi Toilet.
-I bought it, but- -Yes, it's still the same.
Man, I don't even know what young people play these days.
-YES. -YES.
OK, continue.
-Try what you remember- -That stuff,
There's food, there's food, there's food too. The most delicious food that I like to eat the most is ice cream
lemon. I think it's because, because I didn't have air conditioning when I went to school.
-Oh, ok. -So the dish, the lemon ice cream should be more interesting
-than. -Yeah. I experienced a time when I was in school
There is no air conditioning, and I never have to experience that.
It wasn't until I was in third or fourth grade that I had air conditioning.
So during my time, people didn't sell lemon ice cream anymore.
-YES. -Yeah, ok. There is supply and demand.
In the old days without air conditioning, you would hear a lot of noise. In class I will
I heard the sound of birds and then heard the sound in the next classroom.
Uh.
-So the teachers- -Because they didn't close the door.
Teachers will often have drama if the next class or their class opens and it affects them
In the next class, the teachers will scold each other.
-Ah. -YES. Now it's better to close the door.
YES.
-Ok, those are food and toys. -Things related to school.
Then ok. After returning from school, my grandfather or grandmother came to pick me up at the old school gate.
Ah,
In general, it's time to leave
[inhale sound] there will be a lot of noise. In general, you will run down the field
The school plays before leaving, many of them play some more before leaving.
But usually I leaves right away because I has something more interesting to do at home which is playing games
death. I was very excited to go home and play video games.
[laughter] Okay, but in general, when I come out, my family always opens an internet cafe. There
was a wonderful childhood.
-YES. -Yeah,
Besides my house, there are many other internet cafe around Thanh Cong school
and Thanh Cong A, secondary Thanh Cong, Thanh Cong A.
-YES. -But,
Well, my house is relatively big and my house has a lot of customers because it's a shop
nearest net.
Uh,
In the old days, internet cafe were from the time when my grandmother still had a full set
the computer has a very convex screen, the mouse, the keyboard,
-headset and webcam. -Yes, it's also the type of machine it has
-a lump there- -The lump behind.
After that device, it doesn't have a screen.
Right. No, once finished, the case is very small. That means the bigger the case, the bigger the screen
-The smaller the image. [laughs] -Yeah, now, back then it was a very big case
It's small and its screen is a big lump like an old TV.
Yes, that's right.
Done, there's a webcam.
In general, in the past, when I saw women, I only spoke in internet cafe
two hours. One is the sound of hi hi ha ha cursing at each other, the other is the sound of typing on the keyboard
-My sister and I play Audition. -Yeah, pile pile pile pile.
That is very artistic. Done,
After playing for about an hour, dad would pick me up but I wouldn't let me play much.
I feel like dad will time it to pick me up,
Just an hour to finish so I can go home and eat. Then it was time to leave the Citadel area
Cong then,
well, on weekends or at other times
If your grandparents are free, they will take you to Thanh Cong lake to go.
to go for a walk
and learn to ride a bike.
Uh,
In general, at that time, I felt that Thanh Cong Lake was always
also bumpy and also...
-Yeah, it's completely different now. -It's also concrete, it's not paved like stone
-Now. -Yes, before it was concrete and you had to go
-the road is below. -After all, its gate is very difficult.
-Yes, I have to step up one- -Yeah.
That high line. I mean it always looks like it
blocked, it doesn't want people to go in there.
Oh yeah, I also remember the feeling that the door wouldn't open all the way and-
Because I went through the back door, its main door is on the street.
-I never go to the main door. -I will never leave, Thanh Cong
-never go to the main door. -Yes, that's right.
Ex, well, exactly Thanh Cong people will go through the back door because it's closer.
-YES. -Once it's done, the back door will never accept it
I opened it all up because I don't know why. Done like-
-We have to sneak in. -Pull the car in. Well, then start driving the car
Get out there, sneak in and go down. Now I will never have that experience again.
Because follow
With the new government policy, all parks have been abandoned and all of them demolished
-row- -Fence.
-Yeah, the fence. -To go inside.
-YES. -But why did people have to in the past?
I don't understand putting up a fence for the park.
-Probably a lot of drug addicts. [laughs] -Many drug addicts.
Ok.
Describe your feelings when riding a bicycle around Ho Thanh Cong.
-Are you riding a bicycle? -YES.
To be honest, I didn't care about Ho Thanh Cong. Being forced to practice riding a bicycle made me hate it.
Because if I play a sport for two minutes and don't immediately become good at it, I get upset.
Because it is
Playing any sport for two minutes without becoming a very good person is sad.
[laughs] Okay.
See, in the past I was very afraid of riding a bicycle. That's why
In general, I don't like to practice in a place where people will see me fall.
-Yeah. -So I will like to practice behind the yard
-more grandmother. -Yeah.
Both at and outside Thanh Cong Lake, there are many dogs and there are many dogs, well, there is one
What used to be available is now less common than in the past, there was a lot of that fishy smell, sometimes fish
-floating dead. -Ah yes, well, I haven't seen any dead fish lately.
-It smells really good these days. -The ecosystem is ok
-more or no more fish. -So if you remember Thanh Lake
-Tmy job, I will remember the fishy smell- -Fishy.
Dogs do not muzzle
-and the feeling of fear when riding. -And I just want to go home and play online.
-Ok, [laughs] heaven is still at home. -YES.
-Okay. -The internet cafe also has air conditioning.
-Yeah, and the school doesn't have air conditioning. -Correct.
Ok. Ok,
Thank you.